A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office Files of Louis Winnick FA601
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Speeches and Writings, 1957-1967; IV
  - Louis Winnick Review of Rebuilding Cities for Citizens' Housing and Planning Council of New York, 1965 October 26 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - "Place Prosperity vs. People Prosperity: Welfare Considerations in the Geographical Redistribution of Economic Activity," in Essays in Urban Land Economics (Los Angeles, University of California Press, 1966) (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - "New York: A Slumless City", 1966 March 29 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Comments on "The State's Economy and the Constitution," Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, Vol 28, No. 3, 1967 January (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Newsday Op-Ed Submission Re: Housing Policy Debate, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 31)
- Urban Crisis Study, 1986-1988; V
  This series contains Dr. Winnick's research files and handwritten notes. The files were created as part of his work on a Ford Foundation-funded grant and include notes and background on the Sunset Park neighborhood of New York, the history of the Ford Foundation, and drafts for the Urban Crisis Study.
  - Book Reviews -- Winnick's Reviews of Books Sent to Priscilla Lewis at Russell Sage Foundation, 1986 October 23-1987 July 15 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - A Cycle of Outrage (draft chapter "Rehearsal for a Crime Wave" by James Gilbert with corrections), 1987 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Neighborhoods, Sunset Park -- Corrected Draft for Winnick Book on Sunset Park, New People in Old Neighborhoods, 1987 June 8 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Neighborhoods, Sunset Park -- Letter of Agreement, Outline of Study, Notes on Meetings, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Population Shifts -- Drafts for Introduction to Urban Crisis Study Report (1 of 2), 1987 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Population Shifts -- Drafts for Introduction to Urban Crisis Study Report (2 of 2), 1987 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Prospectus for Foundation-Administed Project on Foundations and Urban Crisis, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "Toward a New Definition of Urban Reform" (draft chapter by Kathleen D. McCarthy with revision suggestions), 1988 March 31-April 6 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Underclass -- Handwritten Notes and Article on American's Underclass, 1986-1987 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Winnick Research Notes -- Re: History of Ford Foundation and Programs, American Society and Political Organizations, Urban History Project, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 10)